Joseph Pitts

PHONE: +07 936 050206 | PERSONAL EMAIL: JoePittsy@gmail.com | Work EMAIL: JPitts@lincoln.ac.uk

ABOUT

I am a Computer Science undergraduate at the University of Lincoln. I have been studying Computer Science for over 6 years at GCSE, A-Level and now degree. However, I have been interested in the field much longer than that. I am a hardworking individual with strong technical skills and work well both alone and as part of a team. I am always looking to better myself be that through extra qualifications or side projects.

EDUCATION

LDUCATION			
2018-Present	BSC COMPUTER SCIENCE, The University of Lincoln		
	1st Year Grade: 1st	•	
	Module	Grade	
	Programming & Data Structures	1st	
	Maths for Computing	1st	
	Operating Systems	2:1	
	Algorithms & Complexity	1st	
	Problem Solving	2:2	
	Computer Architectures	1st	
	Web Authoring	1st	
2016-2018	A LEVELS, New College Pontefract		
	Subject Grade		
	Maths B		
	Business B		
	Computer Science C		
2012-2016	GCSE, Brigshaw High School & Lan 10 GCSES including A's in Maths, Co in English	nguage College Computer Science & Physics and a B	

EXPERIENCE

FEB 2020-PRESENT	Associate Developer at the University of Lincoln Working on a Al chat bot service to improve the student life at the University. Unit testing C# / .NET with xUnit.
Nov 2018	Attended the Sir William Siemens Challenge Worked with a team of 6 others over a period of 3 days to build a device that visualised data in new and innovative ways.
2017-2018	Crew Member at McDonalds Maintained high standards of customer service during high-volume, fast-paced operations whilst working with others to ensure fast and yet high quality product.
2015-2016	Volunteer at School Library Volunteered at Brigshaw High School Library as part of my Duke of Edinburgh award.

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TECHNICAL SKILLS

PYTHON

I have over 6 years of experience in Python, it is the first language I learnt. I have used Python in many of my projects, namely in my A-Level project, E-book management software and my add-on to Nautilus (A popular Linux file explorer) to implement the creation of folders from templates.

HTML, CSS & JS

I have over 5 years of experience with web technologies, my A-Level project's user interface was created in Electron and made heavy use of HTML, CSS and especially JavaScript. Furthermore, I have my own Website.

C# I learnt C# in my first year of university. I obtained a first in both modules that used C#. Programming & Data Structures as well as Algorithms & Complexity. I have also have a Microsoft Technical Associates (MTA) Certification in Software Development Fundamentals which tests C# knowledge, Object-Orientated Programming, general software development and more.

I learnt C++ in my second year of university, thanks to pre-reading and self-learning before the year I picked up the language quickly and assisted my peers who were struggling to grasp the language.

VERSION CONTROL

I have set up and managed a GitHub organisation with 7 members and was responsible for code reviews, pull requests and merges. I also use GitHub and version control for my personal projects.

CERTIFICATIONS AND AWARDS

C++

Azure Fundamentals | Microsoft Certified

"Earners of the Azure Fundamentals certification have demonstrated foundational level knowledge of cloud services and how those services are provided with Microsoft Azure." I received this certification on the 11th of May 2020.

Introduction to Programming Using Python | Microsoft Technical Associates (MTA)

The Introduction to Programming Using Python MTA tests that the recipient is well versed in both the Python language but also critical skills needed for a software engineer such as being able to document code to a high standard, and to be able to troubleshoot and error handle. I achieved this certification on the 15th January 2020

Software Development Fundamentals | Microsoft Technical Associates (MTA)

The software development fundamentals MTA tests core software development skills and tests other skills such as Databases, Desktop Applications, General Software Development, Object-oriented Programming and Web Applications. I achieved this certification on the 14th of January 2019.

HOBBIES

I love the outdoors and walking, in my first year of University I was part of the Expedition society where I went on walks around Lincolnshire socialising with the other members and making some fast friends. When I'm not out walking I'm usually in the kitchen cooking, I love challenging myself to not just cook new dishes from recipe books but to develop my own.